Justin Horein

Portland, OR | 608.209.3927 | justinhorein@gmail.com | justinhorein.com | github.com/justinhorein | linkedin.com/in/justinhorein

PROFILE

Hard working and creative individual, interested in improving systems through software development. A recent graduate of the Tech Academy, I am now equipped with experience in a variety of programming technologies. In working through the Tech Academy's 900 hour plus curriculum, including 2 Live Team Projects, I have demonstrated the ability to grasp a lot of knowledge in a short period of time.

EXPERIENCE

Python Django Live Project: Through an internship with Prosper IT Consulting, I built a web app
to help users organize their movie collections. Utilizing a Movie Database API, I constructed a
page that allows users to search movie titles and view the results listed in a presentable format
(Bootstrap Cards). Additionally, I made a page where users can store titles they've already
viewed (utilizing a model and database). Along the way, I participated in a series of standup
meetings in practice of the Agile/Scrum methodology and practiced responsible version control
procedures.

View code here: https://github.com/justinhorein/Python_Django_Live_Project

• C Sharp Live Project: Another internship I did with Prosper IT Consulting, in which I helped develop a website for Theater Vertigo (SE Portland). Most of my effort was spent styling 5 pages for the Ticket Management section of the website where I gained a lot of experience in the front-end, working with Bootstrap in particular. I also completed one back-end story. Like the Django Project, we worked in sprints in practice of the Agile/Scrum methodology.

Couldn't get the code, but you can read an in-depth summary here: https://github.com/justinhorein/C Sharp Live Project/blob/master/C%23%20LP%20Summary. pdf

• **C Sharp Black Jack:** A console app designed as a one-player game of Black Jack. Building this project, I gained lots of experience programming in the Object-Oriented Paradigm. I learned how to organize my code in a library, as well as utilize concepts like Polymorphism, Inheritance, Interfaces, Encapsulation and Abstract Classes.

View code here: https://github.com/justinhorein/C_Sharp_Black_Jack

• React Tic-Tac-Toe: Basically, the official react getting-started tutorial with additional dark/light mode styling. Essentially, it's a game of Tic-Tac-Toe with time travel functionality, meaning you can transport back to past turns and review or even rechoose your move. This was my first hands on exercise with React. I learned a lot of React specific concepts including: how to pass data through props, class vs. functional components, lifting state in-order to store and display game data more effectively and lots of stuff in-between. I also learned general programming techniques such as Data Immutability, that is, storing past records of the games state instead of mutating one set of the games data in order to display past states of the game, essentially enabling the time travel feature. I added dark/light mode functionality as a CSS exercise.

View code here: https://github.com/justinhorein/React-Tic-Tac-Toe

• React Permutations: A web app that takes in a set of anything (animal names, numbers, ice cream flavors) and returns the total number of possible permutations as well as an instance of each permutation. I got to practice recursion while writing the algorithm for this one.

View code here: https://github.com/justinhorein/permutations

• RGB Color Picker: A web app, I built, as an interactive game for testing a user's skills in identifying RGB Color Codes. While building this app, I learned how to select and configure DOM elements as well as write code in the functional programming paradigm.

View code here: https://github.com/justinhorein/RGB-Color-Picker

• **Tic-Tac-Toe:** A vanilla js web app for playing Tic-Tac-Toe complete with sound effects. In building this app, I gained lots of practice with functional programming and DOM manipulation.

View code here: https://github.com/justinhorein/Tic-Tac-Toe

• Hangman: A basic game of hangman for the browser. Apart from practicing my Vanilla JS, I learned how to utilize Scalable Vector Graphics to do basic styling.

View code here: https://github.com/justinhorein/hangman

SKILLS

- LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Python, C#.
- **FRAMEWORKS:** Django, .Net, Express, Entity.
- LIBRARIES: Bootstrap, jQuery.
- **DATABASES:** SQL SERVER, SQLite.
- **IDE:** Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, Jupyter Notebook.

EDUCATION

The Tech Academy

Coding School Portland, OR

Software Developer Certificate

Sept 2019 - May 2020

- Intensive developer training, over 900 hours of study content and drills. Studied Computer Science Fundamentals, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Relational Databases, C# w/.NET framework, Python w/ Django framework, Object Oriented Programming, MVC, Agile/Scrum, Version Control and more.

Pyramind

Music Production School San Francisco, CA

Complete Producer Program

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

Madison College

College Madison, WI

English

Jan 2014 - Aug 2014

WORK HISTORY

- Intern

Prosper IT Consulting | Portland, OR | (503) 206-6915 January 6 - 19, 2020. Also, March 16 - 29, 2020.

 Helped develop a website for a Local Theater Company. Also, developed a web app for keeping track of a movie collection. Both projects were 2 week sprints structured in the Scrum methodology (read more on my GitHub).

Pizzaioli

Pizza Pi Vegan | Seattle, WA | (206) 343-1415 February 2019 - July 2019

Recording Engineer

Word Arts | Seattle, WA | (206) 353-4844 March 1 - March 31, 2019. Also, November 19 - 30, 2019.

 Recorded a glass strings trio for an art installation. Also, recorded a guitar piece for a commercial.

- <u>Deli</u>

Bert's Red Apple | Seattle, WA | (206) 322-1330 March 2018 - February 2019

- Shift Leader

Capriotti's Sandwich Shop | Madison, WI | Since Closed Down April 2016 - December 2016

• Led a team of sandwich artisans to fulfill customer orders and maintain the restaurant.

<u>Counter</u>

Milio's Sandwiches | Madison, WI (Regent St.) | (608) 233-3233 March 2015 - April 2016

INDEPENDENT STUDY

- Currently reading:
 - CODE by Charles Petzold
 - Grokking Algorithms by Aditya Y. Bhargava
- Practicing Algorithms on HackerRank
 - **Profile:** https://www.hackerrank.com/justinhorein